Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Char boldly infiltrated Jaburo,
the Earth Federation Forces Headquarters.
However, with the heroic efforts
of Katz, Letz, and Kikka...
...and with the Gundam's fierce pursuit,
Char had no choice but to retreat.
That damn Char...
A Decoy in Space
The Tianem Fleet will be
departing Jaburo at 2100 hours.
I would like your White Base to leave
two hours before that.
A full two hours ahead, sir?
That's correct. Oh, we'll be sending
three other decoy ships as well.
We're having the Tianem Fleet
head straight for Luna II...
...while the White Base takes the opposite
satellite orbital course.
Then we'll move in to attack
Zeon's space fortress, Solomon.
Yes, sir...
The White Base will depart
at 1900 hours today.
Ensign Mirai, take good care of yourself.
Thank you, Admiral.
Don't worry.
Once Solomon falls,
Zeon's resources will be so low...
...they will inevitably ask for peace
negotiations, and the war will end.
I hope you'll let me find you a husband then.
Uh... Yes, sir.
´
Oh. That's right, you have a fiance.
Forgive my rudeness.
That's okay...
´
He may be my fiance, but
it was arranged by our parents.
Where is he?
I heard that he fled to Side 6
to avoid the war.
I'll have to face it sooner or later.
Yeah.
Welcome back!
The White Base will be departing in an hour.
Have all stations ready to go by then!
Yo! Who's in charge of
the White Base crew?
What do you want with him?
Just tell me where he is!
Mr. Bright! You're wanted.
Hm? What is it?
Lieutenant Sleggar Law.
I've just been transferred here.
Mirai. Have we been notified?
Oh? Um...
Yes, here it is.
My luck must be improving,
if I get to work with such a lovely lady.
Greetings. I'm Mirai Yashima.
Pleased to meet you.
Nice to meet you, miss.
It's Sayla Mass.
Oh?
Looks to me like you're troubled
about some other guy.
What?
Hey, where do I bunk down?
The first step to this great battle
relies on your courageous actions.
Should the Federation Forces
emerge from this battle victorious...
...then our people will remember today
as a turning point in history.
We pray that you will fight well.
He's a great big guy
just like Mr. Ryu was before he died!
I wonder if he's as nice as Ryu though.
I heard he's smart mouthed.
Now then, we'll be taking off soon.
All hands to your stations!
Release the docking locks!
White Base, take off!
Airspace clear! Open hatch!
Wow, look at all the birds!
Pretty!
Look to portside if you have a minute.
It's a flock of flamingos.
I'll record it on video.
All right, you have my authorization.
What's the Trojan Horse up to, Lt. Tokwan?
Sir!
It seems they've left Jaburo
in South America.
Okay.
Move it!
We'll be within combat range in 30 minutes.
Good work.
Was Lady Kycilia quite upset?
Yes, sir.
I thought as much...
If this Zanzibar hadn't been standing by to test the Bigro I couldn't have pursued the Trojan Horse.
Captain Char.
Would you like to see the Bigro?
Sure, show it to me.
I need to come up with a plan.
When it comes to high speed combat,
this Bigro mobile armor...
...puts mobile suits to shame.
We can't build a battle plan
around one machine.
Right. But we've also got two Doms
and an untested mobile armor.
Doms? Aren't they for land combat?
Yes sir! But these are Rick Doms
with powered-up verniers.
They've been remodeled?
Yes. Much more effective than Zaku-types.
Speed it up!
We'll be heading out soon!
Assemble the pilots!
As soon as we know where
the Trojan Horse is headed, we'll attack.
Sir!
The ship pursuing us looks like
a Zanzibar-class warship.
At this rate, they'll catch up in 20 minutes
and we'll be under direct attack.
All right. Stay on this course
and accelerate at Point E3.
Yes. That way it'll look like the White Base
is heading straight toward the moon.
That's the idea.
Char will come.
He'll come for sure.
Sayla, what are you still doing here?!
There's barely time to check the G-Armor.
I'm sorry, sir.
How can you be sure that Char is coming?
Because... There's some fateful attraction
between him and the White Base. Right...?
Are you scared?
Who isn't?
What do you think, Mirai?
I think she's tired,
and that's why she's afraid.
I suppose so.
We have the Trojan Horse's projected course.
Looks like they're headed for the moon.
For the moon?! Are they after
Lady Kycilia's Granada base?
I doubt it.
Sir?
We've been tricked.
The Trojan Horse is just a decoy.
There's probably a different fleet
taking off from Jaburo right about now.
Then we have to change course!
Are you serious? If we turn our backs
on the Trojan Horse, they'll attack us.
We'll have to launch a preemptive strike!
Yes, sir!
Zanzibar located! Maximum magnification.
How many minutes until they attack?
Give me a moment...
At this rate, we'll be under attack
in 2 minutes, 20 seconds.
Amuro and Sayla!
Prepare to launch in the G-Sky and G-Bull.
Have the Guncannon ready on standby!
Open all gun turrets!
Open beam cannons!
Tokwan, are you ready to launch the Bigro?
Sir!
Rick Doms, prepare to launch next!
Tokwan and two others, launching now.
G-Sky, G-Bull Easy, take off at once!
Deploy to the White Base's rear
and destroy the enemy mobile suits!
Looks to me like you're troubled
about some other guy.
If you're doing this to take revenge
on the Zabi family...
...I can't approve of that way of life.
G-Sky! Here I go!
G-Bull Easy, launching now!
Ms. Sayla, distance yourself a little.
If we took a direct hit right now,
they could destroy both of us at once!
Roger!
You've gotta be careful now!
If you go too fast,
gravity will make you plummet.
Remember to fly as if you were ascending.
Thank you! I'll be careful.
They're here!
Rear missiles, intercept quickly!
Here they come!
All right... just you watch!
It's fast!
Can you evade the speed of my Bigro?
I can't believe how powerful it is!
But it's gripping me at a poor angle.
I'll use my beam cannons...
But... what if my brother
is piloting this mobile armor?
N-No, Ms. Sayla, you've got to ascend!
Three enemy mobile suits confirmed.
Please send out the Guncannon, too.
Right! Have Kai launch the Guncannon!
Where's Lieutenant Sleggar?
Yeah? What is it? I'm right below the bridge.
What do you specialize in?
Artillery, fighter craft, take your pick!
Would you take care of
the main cannons, Lieutenant?
On one condition.
What condition?
Turn the White Base toward the enemy!
We're in inertial flight,
so you should be able to do it.
But then they'd catch up with us.
Then I won't do it.
I'm not confident that I'd hit anything.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
Listen well. Just attack for 15 seconds.
if we fire any longer than that, we risk
shooting down our own mobile suits.
This isn't looking good...
We'll get them with the guns at the back!
Yeah!
Yeah. Go get 'em!
The Trojan Horse has gotten better...
I wonder if they have a new captain?
But I think it's impossible.
A civilian entering the military and
joining the Trojan Horse crew.
Artesia...
But the last time I saw her,
she was wearing a military uniform.
Artesia, who was intelligent,
and hated wars more than anyone.
There's no way she'd board
a space warship again.
All right! Halt your fire in three seconds!
Hit your mark!
Sorry. That wasn't on purpose at all.
Hey, Lieutenant Bright!
Lieutenant. Let me remind you...
...that you may be older than me
but I still have command authority. So...
Well, that's obvious.
Thanks a lot.
That's why I'm asking you.
Turn about to starboard so that I can use
the White Base's main cannons!
We can't right now!
Wait a little longer!
The power isn't increasing... Why?!
It doesn't rev up!
Rear missiles!
Firing angle, plus 12 degrees!
Hmph! This is how you
put up a barrage of missiles!
He's maneuvered beneath me?
Here I go!
Talk about guts!
If you keep coming below me...
...you could be pulled down. But...
One of the three enemy machines
is a mobile armor class weapon.
Please hurry with the Guncannon's launch!
Kai! What's taking you so long?!
All right! It's a long story, but I'm ready
and the catapult's okay!
Go back up Amuro and Sayla!
Roger that! Here I go!
Secure the Guntank to the launch exit!
We'll use it as a gun turret! Got that?!
Roger that! I'll inform Hayato.
Bring the White Base about 180 degrees!
Nice going, Lieutenant Bright...
You're doing just fine.
How about taking over at the main cannons?
Ms. Mirai, I'll leave the ship in your hands.
I'm counting on you!
Now, where could they be?
I can't spend the rest of my life
being depressed.
Don't know how Ms. Sayla and Amuro
can keep fighting like that.
A-At this rate...
I've got the upper hand!
It's just a matter of time...
Ms. Sayla...
Mr. Kai!
I'll use this opportunity
to transfer to Gundam.
First, I've got to lower its speed!
I'll give it a try!
A direct hit and she's gone...
but I've gotta stop her from plummeting.
Good!
Ready? I'm starting docking procedures!
Ms. Sayla! Are you all right?!
Yes. But hurry up, Amuro.
Right!
Amuro, what kind of person do you think
is piloting that mobile armor?
Huh? Why do you ask?
N-Never mind.
Amuro! A Dom is coming, so hurry!
Okay!
Amuro!
It's okay! Don't worry, I'll take care of it!
G-Fighter! Docking now complete!
Altitude of mobile suit combat decreasing.
We can open fire on enemy.
All hands, prepare for fleet combat!
Too bad we can't use our J-type missiles.
Prepare cannons!
We'll attack them as we evade their fire!
Aim carefully!
Entering firing range in 30 seconds!
Who has the longer firing range...
us or the Trojan Horse?
I suppose only God knows.
Artesia, I assume you're not on board...
Evade their fire every three seconds.
Roger.
Entering firing range in 20 seconds.
We can fire in 20 seconds!
15 seconds! All hands, prepare to fire!
I don't know how powerful
the White Base's main cannons might be...
...let's take a look.
3...2... 1...
All right!
Here it comes! Return fire!
Wait!
Don't fire yet! Lure them in, and then fire!
Fire missiles continuously!
You persevered well! Now fire!
Damn Zanzibar...
I'll shoot you down somehow!
Now! Head for the Trojan Horse
on a collision course!
But sir...!
We'll be less likely to get hit than
if we weave about. I guarantee it!
Yes, sir!
Zanzibar isn't evading fire!
They're on a collision course!
They're doing what?!
Mirai, evade! Starboard!
It's Char!
He's the only one who would dare
to use these tactics!
It's just as Sayla said! Char's come after us!
The Trojan Horse is losing its nerve!
Artillery, take good aim!
Why you...!
A direct hit!
How do you like that?!
That's for trying to ram into my ship!
Fire rear missiles!
I'm not giving up... or running away!
Where'd the other Dom go?
Where's the Gundam?
All right!
The faster it is, the less accurate the shot.
I'll show you what a Bigro can do.
Hm? I've picked up some baggage!
Could it be the Gundam?!
Wait, if it is... the pilot would have fainted
from the sudden acceleration.
I... I see...
Impossible! Didn't the pilot pass out?!
Where are the other mobile suits
and the Zanzibar?
One of their mobile suits has retreated.
Amuro, are you okay?
They destroyed Tokwan.
Captain Char!
Please let me go after them, sir!
Don't be hasty.
They're like a baby bird
that's wandered into our yard.
There'll be plenty more chances.
Sir!
Now get started on repairs.
Ms. Sayla.
Why did you ask about that?
Huh?
Back there, you asked who I thought
was piloting the mobile armor.
It's just that the enemy was so tough...
That's the only reason.
Is that so...?
We can declare this first stage a success.
I agree. I think we were
able to mislead the Zanzibar.
Impressive, Lieutenant Sleggar.
You were the only one with a direct hit.
That was just a fluke.
I'm more impressed by how you all did.
Yes. Good work, everyone!
The enemy's gotten faster, too.
So how'd it go?
It was scary when we passed the Zanzibar.
Those seemed like Char's tactics.
Char, huh?
Yeah.
Nobody else could've pulled that off.
Man... I really do admire you.
Ms. Sayla, you shot down a mobile suit!
That's quite something.
Oh, come on I just barely...
Don't play it down. I can tell...
You're an incredibly strong person.
Hey, I'm going to take a quick shower.
Okay, but you've only got five minutes.
Zeon will be back in no time at all.
Roger that! Wanna join me, Ms. Mirai?
You'll have to go on your own.
Sure, I hear you.
Yo! Let's go!
- Sure.
- Let's go!
- We're coming with you!
- Yeah!
After shaking off Char's heated pursuit...
...the White Base is met by
a Musai fleet, led by Lieutenant Dren.
Sleggar desperately fights them off...
...and the Gundam stages a fearless charge
against the Musais.
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Breakthrough.
Will you be able to survive?
Next Time
Breakthrough
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...